Clay Harvey Gendron

Analyst & Educator

chg@claygendron.io | (603) 209-0530 | Exeter, NH | LinkedIn | GitHub

Profile

Analyst with 5+ years of experience in Business Intelligence and Data Science, currently working in higher education at Southern New Hampshire University. Driving towards advancing into a Data Scientist or Senior Business Intelligence Analyst role at a forward-thinking organization committed to solving problems that matter. Equipped with knowledge of both Business Intelligence and Data Science, I excel at designing comprehensive analytical solutions encompassing stakeholder engagement, data cleaning/transformation, data visualization, machine learning, and statistical analysis to deliver valuable insights for organizations. I am currently pursuing a MicroMasters through MITx in Statistics and Data Science.

Experience

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

February 2019 – Present

Southern New Hampshire University | Manchester, NH

- Built a student applicant enrollment classification model that directed the business towards a new financial aid strategy that is on pace to increase new student enrollments by 15%.
- Developed a student enrollment and campus revenue forecast model that streamlined the process of refreshing the models and communicating the results and cut the forecast MAPE from 10% to 6%.
- Leveraged Power BI to build an interactive dashboard that visualized each aspect of the campus student experience and its associated revenue and cost implications for the campus president and leadership to use during a strategic review process.
- Utilize SQL to develop complex stored procedures that transform data from multiple source systems into a usable output designed around business definitions.
- Lead efforts to improve reporting UI/UX by establishing best practices and creating report templates for the department.

ADJUNCT PROFESSOR - STATISTICS

September 2021 – May 2022

Southern New Hampshire University | Manchester, NH

• Taught and developed course materials for undergraduate and graduate statistics courses that used modern software, including Python, R, and Power BI.

PRODUCTION SUPPORT ENGINEER

July 2017 – February 2019

Bottomline Technologies | Providence, RI

- Diagnosed and resolved production software issues for a financial technology product, implementing configuration changes as needed.
- Utilized agile software development methodologies to design an improved customer request management process, reducing open ticket time and the number of bugs moved to production.

Education

Skills

CERTIFICATE IN APPLIED DATA SCIENCE

Massachusetts Institute of Technology | June 2022

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA ANALYTICS
Southern New Hampshire University | May 2021

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION Southern New Hampshire University | May 2017

Programming: Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git

Data Science: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Supervised and

Unsupervised Models, Time Series, A/B Testing

Business Intelligence: Power BI, Tableau, Geospatial Visualization, ETL Processes, KPI Development